我们这样擅自外出 会把美国人惹怒的
we will anger the Americans,slipping out like this.
如果你儿子在世界上最著名的学校读书
If your son was a student at one of the greatest universities in the world...
那让他来找你
so make him come to you.
在联合国附近你可以受到保护
You're protected near thev U.N.
-但是一旦我们穿过42街-我很感谢你的关心 Joseph
-Once we cross 42nd street... -as always,I appreciate your caution,joseph,
但你还是多虑了
but,as always,you have far too much of it.
身子放低
Stay down,sir.
趴到地上
Get on the ground.
我只是来送传票的
I'm just serving process.
你老板被告了依据是美国法典第18卷
Your boss is being sued under title 18 of the united states code,
1350节 罪名是种族屠杀 危害人类和酷刑罪
section 1350,for genocide,crimes against humanity,and torture.
总统先生
Mr. President.
这个只是民事诉讼
This is only a civil lawsuit.
我们可以不去管它
We can ignore it.
总统先生
Mr. President.
你想我们为Foreman干活?
You want us to work for foreman?
暂时的
not permanently.
他在准备面试招人替代Taub和13的位置
He is setting up interviews to replace taub and thirteen,
但可能要几个星期
but it might take a couple of weeks.
他们怎么了?
What happened to them?
他辞职了 我不得不炒了13
He quit,and I had to let her go.
你把你女朋友给炒了?
you actually fired your girlfriend?
是的
Yes.
你们俩都有这个能力和你们共事我很放心
You two are both competent,and I know I can work with you.
你真会求爱
You really do know how to woo.
我需要你们
I need you.
有意思的是
It would be interesting.
我们可以一起工作
We could work together.
你知道病人是谁吗?
Did you see who the patient is?
那也是我觉得有趣的原因之一
That's one of the reasons it'll be interesting.
Dibala是世界上最强制的独裁者之一
Dibala is one of the most repressive dictators or the wld.
你治疗死刑犯的时候并没有什么意见
You had no problem treating a guy on death row.
我们治好他 他还会再回去监狱
Who was still in prison after we patched him up.
如果我们治好了Dibala他可能飞回去他的国家大屠杀
We fix dibala,he gets on a plane and executes half his country.
他在镇压南方Sitibi人的民族叛乱
He's been repressing an ethnic rebellion in the south,the sitibi people.
情况还在越变越糟
It's getting worse.
Dibala是美国政府请来的
Dibala is a guest of the U.S.Government.
他还被邀请在联合国发言
And he's been invited to speak at the U.N.
我不是要求你喜欢他
I'm not asking you to love him.
只是要求你做好你的工作而已
I'm asking you to do your job.
可能无法理解
Possibly incomprehensible
当然我在说你炒掉你女朋友这事
Of course,I'm talkg about you firing your girlfriend.
她在我手下工作我们无法好好相处
We weren't getting along with her working under me.
这个很有帮助
This'll help.
Cameron和我也一起工作
Cameron and I work together.
但你不是她的老板
But you weren't her boss.
而且你们后来也没在一起工作了
And you stopped working together.
为什么你不告诉她你错了
Why don't you just tell her you were wrong?
因为我没错
'Cause I wasn'T.
我知道这很难接受
I know how this looks.
我知道这可能使我们分手
I know it might break us up.
总比教我俩确凿无疑分手的好
But that's better than definitely breaking us up,
如果我不这样做我们就真的会分手
which is what would have happened otherwise.
肺部的出血性溃疡
Hemorrhagic ulcers in the lungs.
老天 好像回到了三年前
Oh,my god,it's tee years ago.
这是不是意味着我还是个疯子?
Does that mean I'm still crazy?
你回来了?
You're back?
你看起来很好
You look good.
-我们只是过来帮忙的 因为...-我知道
-We're just helping out because... -I know.
我碰到13收拾东西走人了
I just ran into thirteen while she was clearing out her locker.
节哀顺变啊
My condolences.
虽然她不是这个世界上最辣的女人
Although it's not like she's the hottest woman
我们没有分手
- in the world. -We haven't broken up.
你回来了吗?
Are you back?
一点点
Sort of.
你拿回你的执照了吗?
Did you get your license back?
还要一个月
Not for a month or so.
所以你还是老大
So you'll be in charge.
而我只是做点贡献
I'm just gonna pitch in a little.
Dibala认为有人想要暗杀他
dibala thinks it was an assassination attempt.
钋 就像在伦敦中毒的俄罗斯特工
Polonium,like the russian guy in loon.
FBI检查了他的传票和宾馆房间
Fbi chked the service of process forms and his hotel room.
没有放射性物质的迹象
No radioactivity trails.
胃酸倒流?
Acid reflux?
没有哮喘或者心痛的病史
No history of asthma or heartburn.
他的手上被虫子咬过
he has a bug bite on his hands.
而且他国家盛行疟疾
Malaria's endemic in his country.
先给他用复方蒿甲醚
Let's start him on coartem.
我不想招人不快
I don't want to step on any toes,
但我觉得我对病人要负责
but I guess I do have higher duty to the patient.
有什么你就说吧
If you have something to say,say it.
你匆匆做出一个诊断因为你想赶快离开这个房间
You're rushing to a diagnosis because you're rushing out of this room
因为你不愿和我多待
because you're rightly upset withe.
虽然我不是想出馊主意的那个人
Although I wasn't the one who made that asinine decision.
有什么和医学相关的话你要说吗
Do you have anything medical to say?
因为有呕吐中毒更有可能
Poison fits better because of the vomiting.
可能不是真的虫咬痕迹
Bug bite might not be a bite.
可能是氯痤疮
It might be the start of chloracne.
二恶英暗杀
Assassination attempt through dioxin poisoning.
很难检测出来
It's hard to detect.
很有可能
Fi .
给他用蔗糖聚酯
Start him on olestra.
你为什么不直接了当地说二恶英中毒
You couldn't have just said dioxin up front?
我希望你能自己推测出来
I was hoping you'd get there on your own.
我觉得我们应该找Cuddy谈一下
So I guess we should talk to cuddy.
你确定是二恶英?
You are sure it is dioxin?
不
No.
是我们认为最有可能的
It's our best guess.
蔗糖聚酯能合毒素结合排出体外
The olestra here binds to the poison and flushes it out of your system.
你是哪里人 医生?
Where are you from,doctor?
我是澳大利亚人
I'm australian.
怎么听着有点英国口音?
Do I hear a bit of the british?
大多数人都没留意到
Most people don't notice it.
是的 我在那里混了几年
Yeah,I kicked around there for a while.
在那上的医学院吗?
You went to medical school there?
上了一年神学院
Actually a year of seminary.
然后你不念了
And you left.
我小时候村子里有一个天主教教堂
There was a catholic mission near my childhood village.
我喜欢牧师
I liked the priests.
他们都是好人
They were good people.
但当我的两个妹妹因肺病奄奄一息时
But when my two younger sisters were dying from consumption,
牧师可没什么用
it wasn't more priests we wanted.
我解雇了我的女朋友因为他说他会永远离开
I fired my girlfriend because he said he was gone for good.
我的生活离不开这工作
I need this in my life.
一星期之前 你头也不回地要走
A week ago,it was the last thing you needed.
这是个过程
It's a process.
我在学习
I'm learning.
顺便耍我一通
And screwing me over as you O.
是啊 我正有此意
Yeah,that's why I did it.
对不起
Sorry.
如果你愿意 我可以向13解释
If you want,I'll explain it to thirteen.
他还没准备好
He's not ready.
他没有行医执照
He doesn't have his license.
那他就不能行医
Then he can't practice.
但我们不听他的就太傻了
But we'd be idiots not to listen to him.
你负责病例 他旁听所有鉴别诊断
You're in charge,he sits in on all the differentials.
你拿回你的执照之前 这些都是非正式的
Until you get your license back,this is all unofficial.
不插手治疗 不和病人接触
No procedures,no patient contact.
最后一条我能遵守
Think I can probably deal with that last one.
我解雇你唯一的原因是如果我是上司我们的关系一定会搞糟
The only reason I let you go is because our relationship wouldn't work if I was in charge.
但我马上就不做主了 所以
But I won't be in charge soon,so...
我来是想让你回来工作
I came to offer you your old job back.
我知道
I know.
我很讨嫌
I look bad.
但是情况有变
But circumstances have changed.
我不想要这个工作
I don't want the job.
为什么?
Why not?
因为有个更简单的方法解释你为什么解雇我
Because there's a much simpler explanation for you firing me.
你想和我分手 又没胆量说出来
You wanted to break up with me,but you were too weak to do it yourself.
那我为什么要你回来?
Then why would I try to hire you back?
今晚一起吃晚饭好吗?
Can we please get some dinner tonight?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是来复诊的吗?
you're a follow-up?
你不能治好他
You must not treat him.
Dibala杀了我的妻子
Dibala killed my wife.
她是个工会会员
She was a trade unionist.
在我工作时 他从我们家把她带走
He took her from our home while I was at work.
谁干的?
Who took her?
Dibala的青年劳动联盟
Dibala's youth labor league.
他掩饰说是为了让青年人不在街头游荡
He pretends it's to get young people off the street.
实际上他给十几岁的男孩毒品和酒
But he takes teenage boys from the provinces and feeds them drugs and alcohol
教他们怎么实施虐待
and teaches them how to torture.
两周后她的尸体被丢弃在我的院子里
They dumped her body in my yard two weeks later.
他们强奸了她
They raped her.
他们在她的腹部刻上蟑螂因为她是Sitibi人
They carved inyenzi,cockroach,onto her stomach because she's sitibi.
我很抱歉 但我不能谈论别的病人
I'm very sorry,but I can't discuss other patients.
你应该和律师谈 跟联合国谈
You should talk to a lawyer,talk to the U.N...
让他们袖手旁观吗 就像在卢旺达那样?(94年卢旺达图西部落遭大屠杀)
so they can sit and watch,like they did in rwanda?
有二百万Sitibi族人
There are 2 million sitibi.
他计划将他们全部杀害
He's planning to massacre them all.
他的电台在宣传消灭蟑螂的最后一役
His radio stations are talking about a final war to exterminate the cockroaches.
不能治好他
He can't recover.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
在学校的第一天怎么样了啊?
How was your first day of school?
没有在沙盒上尿尿
Didn't pee once in the sandbox.
和Cuddy怎样?
How was it with cuddy?
你觉得我说的沙盒是什么?
What did you think I was talking abt?
你没有用大蒜
You didn't use garlic.
你昨晚也没有用
You didn't use it last night either.
做佛罗伦萨煎鸡我们一直都加蒜
We always use garlic on chicken florentine.
不加也很好吃
It tastes fine this way.
你好像嗅觉正在丧失
You seem to be losing your sense of smell.
是你理智正在丧失
I think you're losing your sense of mind.
让俺放个屁就能查出你嗅觉有没有问题了
I can check right now if you pull my finger.
不 是--
No,it's the--
你在发明什么医学大谜题吗?
are you inventing some big medical mystery here?
因为如果你又开始幻想...
Because if you're imagining things again...
你昨晚也没有穿鞋
you weren't wearing shoes last night either.
是的 鞋 大蒜 我是吸血鬼Sookie(南方吸血鬼的主人翁)
Yes,shoes,garlic-- I am vampire,sookie.
我让你把回音修好的
I told you to get that echo fixed.
楼下的那位 在你搬来之后
My downstairs neighbor,after you moved in,
开始投诉噪音和煮饭的味道太大
started complaining about the extra noise and the cooking smells.
他叫什么?
What's his name?
我不想你火上浇油
I don't want you making things worse.
他是公寓住户委员会的我还想把花园重新翻修呢
He's on the condo board,and I'm trying to get the back garden renovated.
穿白大褂的教我好多处理和建立联系的技巧
The white coats taught me a whole bunch of fun coping and relating skills.
他不仅仅是个混蛋还是一个失去手臂的越战英雄
He's not only a total jerk,he's a decorated war hero who lost an arm in vietnam.
也就是说 不可能斗得过他的
I mean,there's no winning with this guy.
应对技巧第一条...
Coping skill number one...
全面回避
Complete avoidance.
你开心了?
You happy?
想我了?
Booty call?
不洗澡的话 20分钟我就来
Give me 20 minutes to not shower.
病人突发心脏病
Patient's having a heart attack.
低氧面罩15升
Mask at 15 liters.
觉得你可能想知道
Just tught you'd like to know.
*****
******
拉沙热
Lassa fever.
上回我吞吞吐吐 惹你抓狂了这回我大声说出来
You were mad that I withheld it last time,so I'm saying it right up front.
他已经稳定了 注射40cc的病毒唑咱还赶得及回家看Ellen
He's already stabilized,so 40 ccs of ribavirin,and we're home in time for ellen.
我查过了
I checked.
Dibala的国家没有发生拉沙热病例
There's no lassa in dibala's country.
皮疹退了
The rash is gone.
你关于二恶英的理论站不住脚了
It rules out your dioxin theory.
他在发轻烧 再加上心脏病 肺内出血
He's running a slight fever,which we can add to the heart,plus the lung ulcers.
埃博拉? 马尔堡病?
ebola?Marburg?
- 潜伏期不会有这么长- 你说吧
-Too long an incubation period. -Yes?
难道他不会旅行?
Don't people sometimes travel?
比方去个被尼日利亚拉沙镇的病毒波及的地方
To places that have,you know,a fever that originated in the nigerian town of lassa?
他在过去两年只去过三个国家
He's been to three other countries in the last two years:
本国 津巴布韦和埃及的沙姆沙伊赫
Here,zimbabwe,and sharm el-sheikh,egypt.
同样没有拉沙热流行
No lassa there either.
真不巧啊
Again.
锥虫病?
Trypanosomiasis?
没有睡眠障碍
No sleep disturbances.
但与症状最相符
But fits best with the symptoms.
从地域上看--又怎么了?
And it's geographicall the most-- what?
去埃及是为了参加非盟会议
The egypt visit was for the african union meeting,
我猜他和来自非洲的人会谈
where I'm guessing he was meeting people from africa.
包括利比亚派出的外交官员
Which includes liberia,which sent some members of their foreign ministry,
而利比亚刚刚爆发了股藓
which has itself just been hit by an outbreak of jock itch.
哦 错了
No,wait.
不是股藓
Not jock itch.
拉沙热
Lassa fever.
开始用病毒唑
I'll start the ribavirin.
瞧我这不是大声说出来了
I did say it up front.
老伙计又凑在一块 真是不错啊
It's great to have the old team back together again,huh?
昨天说是下毒
yesterday,it's poisoning.
今天是拉沙热
Today,lassa fever.
- 专家该不该- Joseph!
Maybe a specialist-- joseph!
别怪他
Leave him alone.
医生会尽力的
These people know what they are doing.
你结婚了么?
Are you married,doctor?
没
No.
你有女朋友?
You have a girlfriend.
是的
Yes.
从你斟酌的语气和那个姑娘复杂的神情看
Judging by your tentative answer and the complicated expression on her face,
过道里的那个应该就是你女朋友吧
I believe that is she,standing in the hallway.
我接到Princeton总院Douglas那儿打来的电话
I got a call from douglas' department at princeton general.
喊我去面试
They want me to interview with them.
奇怪的是 我上周刚打去问过
Which is weird,because when I called last week,
那时还说不招人
they said they had nothing available.
所以我连简历都没寄
So I never sent in my resume.
Douglas欠我情
Douglas owes me a favor.
正常人道歉送巧克力
Most people send ctes.Cola
我本打算在你家楼下整夜举着唱机
I'd stand outside your apartment all night holding up a boom box,
可你说过你讨厌80年代的歌
except you told me you hate '80s music.
说到晚饭?
So about dinner?
我明晚有空
I'm free tomorrow night.
我还在纳闷哪儿来的噪音
I was wondering what that noise was.
原来是该死的拐杖
It's the damn cane.
你好 我是Greg
And I'm greg.
你这玩意乒乒乓乓 我可睡不着
And I can't sleep with you banging around with that thing.
你不是在埋怨我这根拐杖动静太大吧
You're not actually saying that I have too loud a cane?
有这么难理解么?
Is that hard for you to understand?
敢情你没注意它可不是踢踏舞鞋还包着橡皮头呢
Only in the sense that it has a rubber tip on the end and not a tap shoe.
你想惹毛我
Now you're getting cute with me.
好啦 起头不算 从新来过
Okay,we started badly.
我为噪音道歉 我会想办法更安静些
I apologize for the noise,and we will try to figure out a way to be quieter¡ª
别想来这套
and a thousand other things I don't give a crap about.
要是不让我清静 我有你好看
Now you keep it down,or we're gonna have trouble.
你呼我?
you paged me?
这是Ama
This is ama.
你从我们国家来 现在住在这儿
She is from our country,but she lives here now.
我们希望用她的血
We'd like you to use her blood.
干什么?
For what?
她两年前得过拉沙热 后来康复了
She recovered from lassa fever two years ago.
我们的卫生部长建议
Our health minister has advised us that
用含有抗体的血浆比病毒唑有效多了
plasma from one who has the antibodies is much more effective than ribavirin.
这是签过名的同意书
This is a signed consent form.
你会用她的血吧?
Will you take her blood,please?
不
No.
我愿意的
I want to do this.
你明白我们将用你的血来治疗Dibala总统
you understand that we would be using your blood to cure president dibala.
我明白
I know.
你是Sitibi人么?
Are you from the sitibi people?
我是Sitibi
I am sitibi.
他们威胁你?
Did they threaten you in some way?
你的家人回国了?
Your family members back home?
请让我捐血吧
Please let me give the blood.
求你们
Please.
就这么办吧
Do it.
她是被威逼的
She's being coerced.
就算她是 我宁愿背负插针头的罪也不愿害死她的家人
If she is,I'd rather have a needle prick on my conscience than the death of her family members.
拦住他
Don't let him in there!
够了 制服他了
That's enough!We got him.
你没事吧?
You all right?
这人是谁?
Who is that man?
他中弹了?
He shot him?
没
No.
你需要律师
you need a lawyer.
可以让法庭指派
You can get a court-appointed.
能帮到你
They can help you.
没人能帮我
I can't be helped.
你干了件蠢事
You did a stupid,terrible thing.
但基于你妻子的遭遇
But given the circumstances with your wife,
会轻判的
you could get a reduced sentence.
她不是我妻子
She wasn't my wife.
那她是谁?
Then who was she?
他们没告诉我们她的名字
They never told us her name.
他的人逼我们对这女人犯下的罪
What his men made us do to that woman...
他将要残害所有的Sitibi人
he is now going to do to all the sitibi.
你可能会死的
you could have gotten killed.
他不是要伤害我
He wasn't going to hurt me.
他在医院里开枪
He fired a gun in the hospital.
抱抱
Come here.
或者下次别大声示警
Maybe next time don't yell out that warning.
眼睛出血是因为淋巴结肿大压迫了视网膜静脉
The bloody eye was from an enlarged lymph node blocking the retinal vein.
我们疏导了循环
We restored circulation,
意味着在心脏 肺 发热之外 还得加上淋巴
but it means we've got to add lymph involvement to the heart,lungs,and rising fever.
我准备静静坐着
I'm just gonna sit here quietly.
为什么?
Why?
我发觉我不由自主地损害您的威严
I feel like I've been inadvertently undermining your authority,
所以我就旁观
so I'm just gonna observe.
不说一个字
Not gonna say a rd.
心脏问题可能指向肉状瘤病
The heart could point to sarcoidosis.
我猜X光片没有显示肺门淋巴结肿大否定了肉状瘤病
I'm thinking the x-rays indicate a lack of hilar adenopathy,which rules it out.
金黄色葡萄球菌感染?
Staph aureus?
不
no.
因为...
Because...
他...
he...
抽烟?
smokes?
他模仿的是体温计
He's miming a thermometer.
他意思是体温不够高
He says the fever's not high enough.
那是其他的感染
So some other infection.
他错了
he's wrong.
发烧容易引导我们去想感染
The fever could be misleading us into thinking infection.
说啊
Talk.
淋巴瘤都符合
It could all fit with lymphoma.
请你跨开双腿 我好搭成H
Um,I need you to spread your legs so I can do an H.
淋巴瘤不可能
Can't be lymphoma.
乳酸脱氢酶值正常
Ldh is normal.
他肝脏功能完好
He's got good liver function.
掩盖了乳酸脱氢酶值升高
It's masking the elevated levels.
活检淋巴结
Biopsy the lymph node.
证实一下
Check it out.
有道理
Makes sense.
看来你不需要我
I guess you don't need me.
要不你顺手拉上百叶窗吧
Oh,by the way,you might want to close the blinds.
有点儿太亮堂了
A little bright in here.
好巧不巧 他居然认为你是个无赖
It's just a wild coincidence that he thought you were a rude jerk.
得了 要相信我是无辜的
Come on.Give me the benefit of the doubt.
你说他蛮不讲理的
You said he's a jerk.
我几乎没还嘴
I barely talked.
你动嘴皮子了
You talked!
我只想早晨醒来在微微鼓泡的宁静喷泉旁 呷口Espresso
All I wanted was to sip morning espresso next to a peaceful,burbling fountain.
你可以呷着极品干邑
You could be sipping courvoisier
倚在花花公子乐园的复制品旁只要你掌握了他的弱点
next to a replica of the playboy grotto if you tell him what you got on him.
我可没有他的把柄
I don't have anything on him.
我根本不想抓他的把柄
I don't want anything onim.
据说他去过越南?
The closest he's been to vietnam?
可以在街角那个馆子订香脆面
Ordering the mee krob at that place on the corner.
香脆面是泰国菜
Mee krob is from thailand.
没错
Exactly.
你在想什么?
What did you do?
为什么怀疑他说谎呢?
Why do you think he's faking?
我看见了他的信
I saw his mail.
你撬了他的门?
Your broke in?
没有
No.
他当时拿着信
He was holding it.
私人医疗保险
Private medical insurance.
不是退役军人管理局寄来的
Not from the V.A.
再说 他也就五十来岁
Plus,he's got to be early 50s.
过分年轻的老兵
He's too young to be a vet.
所以我又进一步调查了一下
So I looked further.
你真的撬了门
You did break in.
上网查
Online.
所有退伍记录里都没他的名字
There's no reference to him in any of the vet records.
他为什么要假装是退伍兵呢?
Why would he fake being a veteran?
看看你是怎么对他的吧
Just look how you're acting.
多年来人们都为了这混蛋而蹑手蹑脚
People have been tiptoeing around this jerk for years.
通常我们都对肢残人士说去死吧
Normally,we'd all tell the amputee to go screw himself.
同情给受害者 谄媚献给英雄
Victims get pity,heroes get adulation.
这样多好
It's way better.
谢谢你帮我解决邻居的事
Thank you for trying to help me out with my neighbor.
忘了越南这回事吧
Now forget the vietnam stuff.
我可以证明的
I could prove this.
但你不行因为你要忙着给他写封道歉信
But you won't because you'll be too busy writing him a letter of apology
放到门前 但是不要敲门
and dropping it at his door without knocking at his door.
我什么都没做啊
I didn't do anything.
那家伙就是个混蛋
That guy's a total ass.
这才是关键
Which is the point.
对你喜欢的人友善很容易
It's easy to be nice to people you like.
对你讨厌的人友善 这就是个本事了
But being nice to people you hate,that's a skill.
照做吧
Do it.
谢谢你救了我的命
Thank you for saving my life.
那个要杀你的人
The man that tried to kill you,
说你在筹划一场大屠杀
he said that you were preparing a massacre.
Sitibi人是我的子民
The sitibi are my countrymen.
我在对抗一场游击战争
I am fighting a guerilla war.
另外一种说法也叫种族屠杀
In a way that's being called genocide.
二十年前就是这些Sitibi造反派占领了南部
20 years ago,these same sitibi rebels took over the south,
他们屠杀了上万人现在他们又要重演历史
they massacred tens of thousands,and they would happily do it again.
我在维持秩序
I'm trying to impose order.
我在阻止一场种族屠杀
I'm trying to prevent a genocide.
种族屠杀
Genocide.
我最小的儿子在这儿念书
My own son,my youngest,he is a student here.
他很多年没跟我说过话了因为你们报纸上的报道
He hasn't spoken to me in years because of what he read in your newspapers.
但他看到的不是真的
But what he read is not true.
那你的青年劳动联盟呢?
What about your youth labor league?
这桩事我犯错了
There I was at fault.
我雇了一些满腔热血的人他们逾越了界限 违背了本意
I hired men,who,in their zeal,stepped over the line,and there were abuses.
但这种事不会再发生了
But that will not happen ain.
有人吗?
Hello?
怎么样了?
How's it going?
细胞核看上去正常
Normal-looking nucleus.
你怎么样了?
How's it going with you?
你开玩笑说让那人杀了Dibala时我很担心
It worried me when you joked about letting that man shoot dibala.
我没有开玩笑
I wasn't joking.
你不应该想杀任何人
You can't want to kill anyone,
-特别是你的病人-这么希望很自然...
-especially not your own patient. -It's only natural to feel he should
不 这样很不正常
no,it's completely unnatural.
只有精神病人才能杀人后不自我崩溃
Only psychopaths can kill other people without ving some sort of breakdown.
有正当理由时则不是 比如说军人
Not when it's justified.Look at soldiers.
即使是有正当理由时
Even when it's justified.
我在害他死吗?
Am I trying to kill our patient?
当然没有
Of course not.
但如果他死了我要假装这是世界的损失吗?
But if he died,am I supposed to just pretend that wouldn't be good for the world?
细胞分化整齐
The cells are neatly differentiated.
不是淋巴瘤
This isn't lymphoma.
我就说我闻到一股甜到腻的枫糖味还有公费医疗的味道
thought I had detected the sickly sweet smell of maple syrup and socialized medicine.
闻起来像是
It smells like.
胜利的味道
victory.
你房间里的大旗促使我和你的清洁工聊了聊
That big flag in your place prompted me to chat with your housekeeper.
原来你是北大荒人啊
Turns out you're a citizen of the great white north.
你闯入了我家?
You broke into my apartment?
严格来说 没有
Technically,no.
嗯 严格来说 是 但仅仅两步
Well,technically,yeah,but two steps.
-算不上--你得进监狱了
Hardly-- you're going to jail.
说到这个你知道你要获刑六个月和十万元罚款吗?
Speaking of,you know what can get you six months and a $100,000 fine?
假称自己得过越战勋章
Falsely claiming that you won a medal in vietnam.
你觉得我在说谎?
You think I'm faking?
加拿大没有往越南派兵 你个笨蛋
Canada did not send troops to fight in vietnam,you idiot.
他们派了兵去执行巴黎和约
They sent troops to reinforce the '73 peace accords,
在那儿我试图解救一名踩上地雷的十二岁少年
which is where I tried to free a 12-year-old boy who stepped on a land mine.
36年之后的每一秒钟
36 years later,every second,
我都能感觉到还紧拽着那孩子的胳膊手上传来刺骨的疼痛
I feel the pain in my hand like I'm still grabbing that boy's arm,
即使我已经没了胳膊
even though my arm isn't there.
所以 我没有撒谎
So,no,I'm not faking.
我顶你 加油吧 红枫飘飘
On a related note,go maple leafs.
有活检结果了吗?
Did you get the biopsy results?
是淋巴瘤吗?
Is it lymphoma?
不是
No.
那我们就得继续查了
So we have to move on.
-感染 或许是自体免疫病-有活检结果了吗?
-Infection,perhaps autoimmune. -Did you get the biopsy results?
是的 我刚告诉你的
Yes,I just told you.
是淋巴瘤吗?
Is it lymphoma?
Cameron和Chase如何?
Camen and chase?
他们很喜欢诊断
They both really like diagnostics,
我想他们更喜欢看House折磨我
and I think they both really like watching house torture me.
无论如何 谢谢你理解我
Anyway,thank you for understanding about the job.
我只能两害相权取其轻
I had two really crappy alternatives.
还有第三个选择
There was a third.
是什么?
What's that?
你可以放弃这个职位
You could have stepped aside.
那我们俩都会失业的
We both would have lost our jobs.
你可以让Cameron或Chase取代你当部门领导
You could have asked cameron or chase to take your place.
他们可不乐意
They wouldn't have wanted to.
你不是说他们喜欢诊断吗?
You just said they both really like diagnostics.
你想回去工作?
You want to go back in time?
我想解决问题
I want to make this work.
我想尽量去理解你
I want to understand you.
你知道 你上次的决定让我作何感想
I mean,you know how you made me feel.
如果让你重新选择...
If you could do it again...
我的决定是正确的
I made the right decision.
我需要你的专业意见并希望你保密
I need your confidential medical opinion.
总统现在能正常思考吗?
Is the president capable of thinking clearly?
显然不能 目前来说
Obviously not,right now.
那么以后呢?
Will he ever be?
我认为...
I think...
神经损伤无法复原而且他现在每况愈下
neurons don't grow back,and he's already ihis clinE.
所以他说的话 下达的命令
Anything he tells you,any command he gives,
也许只是一个病入膏肓的老人的胡言乱语罢了
how will you ever know it's not just the delusions of a sick,mad,dying old man?
病人发高烧了
He just started spiking a fever.
是硬皮病
It's scleroderma.
你这次不搞花样来揭晓谜底了?
You don't have some clever way of telling me this time?
病人快死了
Patient's dying.
我不会胡搅了
I'm done with clever.
你看他的皮肤
Look at his skin.
对75岁的人来说 未免太紧致了
It's tight for a 75-year-old.
就凭一张入院照?
Based on his admission photo?
太主观了
Bit subjective.
高热表明有感染
Fever points to infection.
而且他的手指有结节
And now he's got nodules his fingers.
是芽生菌病
That's blastomycosis.
就凭结节?
Nodules?
亏你还说我凭皮肤下结论主观呢
And you're calling tight skin subjective?
我同意Foreman
I'm with foreman.
如果是硬皮病做头部CT时会发现真菌球
We would have seen fungus balls on the head ct.
真菌病变可能被忽略了
Fungal lesions can be missed.
我们可以做个检查确认
we could settle this with a test.
抗着丝点抗体指向硬皮病
Anticentromere antibodies would point to scleroderma.
只是指向 不能证实
Point to,not prove.
他的体温太高了
And his fever's too high.
必须马上着手治疗
We have to treat him now.
如果治疗有误 只会加重病情
We treat wrong,we could send this disease into overdrive.
你也同意是硬皮病
You're with me on the scleroderma.
是的 但我不关心这人死活
I guess.I just don't care enough about the patient
- 也不想费力气去说服任何人- 晓得了
-to waste my time trying to convince anyone. -We get it.
你不喜欢这个人你不想插手这个病例
You don't like the guy,you didn't want to work on this case.
但你还呆在这里
And yet you're still here.
何不立场坚定些
Why don't you take a stand?
你要么帮忙 要么给我闭嘴
Either do something about it or shut up.
照你说的芽生菌病治好了
Treat him for blasto if you want.
我去找Cuddy
I'll get cuddy.
- 我可以说服她- 这不是民主选举
I can convince her-- this isn't a democracy.
我不管你找谁
I don't care who you get.
至少目前为止 这还是我的部门
At least for right now,this is my department.
照芽生菌病治疗
We're treating him for blasto.
给他注射两性霉素B
Start him on amphotericin B.
如果你在我的静脉里注入气泡...
If you inject my I.V.With an air bubble...
你想干什么?
what are you doing?
会引发我的另一次心脏病
I will have another heart attack.
没人能发现
No one will know.
放开她
Let her go.
你对我的上校说我是个垂死老人 不能听我的
You tell my colonel I'm a sick,dying old man who can't be trusted.
我没有说...
I didn't say...
你先前做的 无异于塞给他一把枪让他架在我脑袋上
you were trying to put a gun in his hand and point it at my head.
但现在枪在你的手上
The gun is now in your hand.
两者有着本质 而不是道德上的区别
That is a practical difference,not a moral one.
如果你想我死 就开枪吧
If you want me dead,then pull the trigger.
但要自己动手 可没这么容易了
It is not so easy when you have to do it yourself.
Allison
Allison.
我想 我并不想你死
I guess I didn't want you dead.
如果你敢再碰我妻子我就把你赶出去
You touch my wife again,I'll kick your ass out into the street.
我不管你是什么人
I don't care who you are.
我帮了她一个忙
I did her a favor.
我让她看到了自己的本心
I showed her her true character.
她人比你好得多
She's a better person than you are.
她太软弱 无法践行自己的信仰
She is too weak to act on her beliefs.
但这不是她的错
But that is not her fault.
大部分人如此
Most everyone is.
包括我的顾问
Even my own advisors.
我的上校
My own colonel.
他们只会谈判 磋商 签署协议
All they do negotiate and debate and sign treaties.
摆出求和者姿态
They are appeasers.
- 要知道 我们此刻正被杀手 叛军--- 你指"蟑螂"?(独裁者对少数族裔的称谓)
And all the while,we are beset by assassins and traitors,the scum-- cockroaches?
你会怎样对待他们?
What are you going to do about them?
对你来说 敌人意味着什么?
What is an enemy to you?
垂涎你职位的年轻医师?
Some younger physician who covets your office?
在我的世界里 敌人便意味着威胁 流血和死亡
In my world,there are dangers and bloodshed and death.
这让你成长为一个男人
And that makes you a man.
男人应该敢于抉择
And men make choices.
而你的抉择就是派遣一帮酒醉的狂热孩子
And your choe is to send bands of drunk,
去屠杀一整个民族?
crazed children to massacre an entire people?
如果你不知道答案 就不要提出问题
Don't ask me questions you don't want to know the answer to.
我救了你的命
I saved your life.
我有权知道你会怎么--
I deserve to know what you're planning¡ª
为了保护我的国家 我不惜任何代价
whatever it takes to protect my country.
你闯入他家了?
You broke into his apartment?
不算闯入
I didn't break in.
真希望我能相信你
I wish I believed you.
我可以补救
I can fix this.
我已经做了
I already did.
他本来要去告你
He was going to press charges.
但是...
But...
我向他保证 你会搬走
I promised him you'd leave.
你要赶我走?
You're kicking me out?
我会向你的医生解释 但...
I'll explain it to your psychiatrist,but...
是的 你得搬到别处去
yeah.You got to go somewhere else.
House 我知道一旦捅出漏子你的所谓补救...
House,I know when things go wrong,usually you just double down
只会让事情加倍糟糕但这次会把你送进号子
and get more involved,but here you could go to jail.
我相信 你已经变了很多能够体会到我的良苦用心
And I truly believe that you've changed enough to know this is the right thing.
我们得抽个血样
We need a blood sample.
给他做抗着丝点抗体测试
We got to do the antictromere antibody test.
结果会证明House是对的
It'll show house is right.
是硬皮病
It's scleroderma.
为什么你肯治他了?
Why are you doing this now?
因为我不想杀死他
Because I didn't want to kill him.
你说的对
And you're right.
我必须用行动表明立场
I have to take a side.
所以我决定尽力挽救他的生命
So I'm going to do what I can to keep him alive.
我去给你取血样
I'll get you the blood.
抗着丝点抗体测试呈阳性
Positive for anticentromere antibodies.
我们得停用抗真菌素马上给他上类固醇
Better get him off the antifungals and onto steroids immediately.
我说过了 只是指向硬皮病
I told you before,this only points to scleroderma.
不能证实
It doesn't prove it.
你打算忽略测试结果?
You're just gonna ignore the test?
芽生菌病更为符合
Blasto still fits best.
虽然单凭这个无法确诊
I know it'sot conclusive,
- 但加上其它的症状--- 我主意已决
but when you put it with all the other evidence¡ªI've made my decision.
你告诉13 你开除她是不对的了吗?
Have you told thirteen you were wrong to fire her?
现在为什么要说这个?
What does that have to do with anything?
我们共事了很长时间我深知你是个理智的人
I've worked with you long enough to know you're reasonable.
能勇于承认错误
You can usually admit when you're wrong.
但在你内心深处
But there's some deep part of you,
一旦发现 你人生至关重要的一个决定是错误的
that when you find you're wrong about the most important decisions you've made,
你就会失去安全感 并对其他人筑起防线
you get insecure and you just retrench.
你想搞砸你的恋情没问题 这是你的权利
If you want to mess up your relationship,that's your right,
但搞砸诊断 我们的病人就会死
but you mess this up,our patient dies.
给他换类固醇
Switch him tsteroids.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi,honey.
你今天过的如何?
How was your day?
早安
Morning.
首先 是我不好
First of all,my bad.
我最近经历了很多事
I've gone through this whole thing recently.
我不想闷场
I don't want to bore you.
长话短说: 我很想去改变一些东西
Short version: I'm really trying to work on some stuff.
这事对我来说是倒退了
This is a definite setback.
但公平点吧 你也有部分责任
Although,in fairness,you really did make it tough.
你失去的那只手有幻肢痛对吧?(被切除的肢体仍感觉疼痛)
Phantom pain in your missing arm?
你药箱里有五种不同的止痛药
Five different kinds of painkiller in your medicine cabinet.
你面前的神奇魔术箱就是专治这个的
That's what this magic box of neurological trickery is for.
面对一个绑架你的疯子你还是乖乖就范的好
This would be a lot easier if you do what the crazy guy who tied you up says.
把手伸进去
Put your hand in there.
看看吧
Now look.
镜像魔术
It's mirror magic.
你的手又回来了
Your arm is back.
现在同时握紧两只拳头
Now clench both your fists at the same time.
握紧
Clench.
用力握紧
Real hard.
如果你相信上帝祈祷这能管用吧
If you believe in god,pray that this is gonna work.
还可以顺便问问他为什么炸断你的手
You might also want to ask him why he blew off your arm.
好了么?
Ready?
放开吧
Now let go.
噢 上帝啊
Oh,my god.
不痛了
It relaxed.
36年来 疼痛一直缠绕着我
For 36 years,I've been in pain.
现在终于消失了
And it's finally gone.
噢 上帝
Oh,my god.
谢谢你(镜箱疗法在临床上证实有效)
Thank you.
氧浓度下降到88
O2 sat's down to 88.
进入总支气管
Going through the main stem bronchus.
进入右肺上叶
Into the right upper lobe.
请他们出去
Get them out of here.
不!
No!
没事的
it's okay
出血点
Bleeder.
灼烧
Cauterizing.
搞定了?
Got it?
是的
Yeah.
拿电击板来!
Get the paddles!
重新进入
I'm going back in.
出什么事了?
What is happening?
他的肺部出血不止
he's bleeding into his lungs.
充电
Charging.
另一出血点
Another bleeder.
我能搞定
I can get it.
慢着
Hold on.
还有第三个
There's a third.
天啊 到处都是
God,there's a dozen.
电击他
Shock him.
让开
Clear.
充电 让开
charging.Clear.
你想蜷作一团哭鼻子的话躺椅更舒服一点
You want to curl up and cry,the lounge chair's a little more comfy.
我把药换了
I switched his meds.
我认为我错了于是停用了抗真菌素
I thought I was wrong,so I took him off the antifungals.
照你说的 给他上类固醇
Put him on steroids like you said.
你知道这意味着什么
You know what that means.
我改变主意得太晚
I was too late.
或者我一开始才是对的
Or I was right in the first place.
那么说 你要么是因为对自己的诊断缺乏自信 害死了病人
So either you killed him by not having confidence in your opinion,
要么是因为过分固执己见而害死了他
or you killed him by being too attached to your opinion.
如果你和我一样的话--顺说 的确有几分--
If you're anything like me-- and,by the way,you are--
你必须找出真相
you need to know which.
他的尸体锁在太平间
He's under lock and key in the morgue.
他的政府要让自己的医生做尸检
His government wants their own doctors to do the autopsy.
他们明天就会把他运走
They're taking his body out tomorrow.
我聘用你的其中一个原因
There's a reason I hired you.
就是你知道怎么跟锁头打交道
You used to know what to do with a locked door.
我去了趟太平间想重做抗体检测
I went down to the morgue to rerun the antibodies test.
我们做了两遍
We ran it twice.
但我进不去
Turns out I couldn't get in.
荷枪实弹的警卫看守着
They had an armed guard.
但我看到了这个
But I saw this.
进入太平间的登记
It's a sign-in sheet from the morgue.
上面有你的签名
Your signature.
今早9:45
9:45 this morning.
正好是你们做检测之前
That's right before you guys ran the test.
你去那里干什么?
What were you doing there?
跟进一个门诊病例
Follow-up on a clinic case.
什么病例?
What case?
你真觉得这重要吗--
You think this is really important¡ª
太平间其中一个病人是死于硬皮病的70岁老妇
one of the patients in the morgue was a 70-year-old woman who had scleroderma.
如果你和Cameron取的是这位老妇的血样
You and cameron,if you took that woman's blood,
你们就能伪造检测结果导致我们采用错误疗法
you could have messed up the test results so we treated dibala for the wrong disease.
Cameron和这事无关
Cameron had nothing to do with it.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
他要屠杀Sitibi人
He was going to kill the sitibi.
把他们赶尽杀绝
Every last one of them.
我不管他要干什么
I don't care what he was going to do.
我只知道 他把性命交到了我们手上
He came to us and put his life in our hands.
我们做的所有好事...
All the good we've done...
拯救的每一条生命...
every life we've saved...
如果他康复出院 死于他手的万千亡魂将会让从前的善举变得毫无意义
it would have meant nothing if we just sent him off to kill hundreds of thousands of people.
新闻上说了
Look at the news.
温和派力量开始占上风
The moderates are taking over.
和平谈判重现希望
There's hope for peace talks.
如果你对外宣布 我伪造了检测结果Dibala会变成殉道者
You tell the world that I faked this test,dibala becomes a martyr.
大屠杀便会开始
The massacres begin.
如果为你隐瞒 我便与帮凶无异
I cover this up,I become your accomplice.
你以为我会为你背上这种罪咎?
You think you can guilt me into that?
你向警察举报之前麻烦告诉我一声...
If the cops are going to come for me,please warn me...
好让我向我妻子道别
so that I can tell my wife first.
Chase...
你真以为 你可以褫夺一个人的生命而不必为之付出代价?
you really think you can kill another human being without any consequences to yourself?
不
No.
大部分美洲鳄生活于美国东南部
american alligators are mostly found in the southeastern united states.
我邻居打电话来了
My neighbor called.
他听起来...
He sounded...
很高兴
happy.
这不挺好
That's nice.
更好的是 他同意扩建花园
Even nicer,he's approving the garden expansion.
更更好的是 即便你不搬走他也不打算告你了
And even more nicer,he's not going to press charges even if you don't move out.
你对他做了什么?
What did you do to him?
我很乖
I was nice.
你真想知道?
You really want to know?
我想...
I think...
我只管相信你好了
I want to give you the benefit of the doubt.
美洲鳄猎杀小型动物为食
alligators eat fish,birds,turtles,snakes,mammals,and amphibians.
噢!
Both: Oh!